Hello there, my name is Ian McCullough,
and this is the close-out video
for Sync.Land Project 11 00272,
funded in Project Catalyst Fund 11 under
the Cardano Use Cases: Concept category.
So the problem that we solved
with this Catalyst proposal was an
independent musician has no plain way
to license a song for a film
or game or a livestream
without a traditional publisher
or legacy system.
And the buyer, the streamer,
the game developer, the filmmaker,
has no plain way to get the provable
license and know what it's for and when,
and all that is very confusing.
So we have streamlined
that entire process,
and our approach was to build
it around a marketplace structure
where it's peer-to-peer, open,
and the artist directs
its licensing straight to the buyer.
We've been able to have 653
individual tracks of different genres,
and we've been able to amass 85 different
artists in 26 different countries.
And I think that's the KPI
that matters the most.
Really, it's the supply.
The part of the reason
why it's been successful
has been the advent of ChatGPT
and optimizing for LLMs.
This is the llms.txt.
So let's start by logging in,
and I will log into my artist account,
where we'll be able
to see my dashboard here,
where I can see all my albums.
I can manage the licensing,
but the other part of the artist's
experience primarily is through
their pitches. And this is all through the
economic function from the demand side,
the buyer side. This is through briefs.
These are sync opportunities
that are available
through our music supervision partners.
So these are real briefs
that we accept pitches from artists.
There has already been 194
pitches from 29 artists.
And when these licenses
get certified on chain,
this is a public endpoint
that needs no account or anything.
This is the receipt that we store
that points to the transaction itself
and the assets and the UTXOs involved.
And here it is on Cardano preprod.
We have three tiers, the free syncs,
so personal, educational, nonprofit,
people that are doing user-generated
content or small indie developers.
And then there is a cap
and what they call a step deal
into commercial licensing if it's enabled,
where you just pay one-time fee.
And then there are the custom
and exclusive.
And of course,
it's all verified on chain on Cardano.
The last piece that we'll go
through is the world of streaming
and streamers.
This is our big push into that world.
A public API connecting other
applications to license on the fly.
OK, so we get a link
and paste it in and then we're able
to access the songs through our playlist.
And open up the electronic playlist
and we can see here's
the first song in the playlist.
So if they go to the next song, boom,
it goes to the next song, pause,
pauses, play, play. Some closing
remarks here about this project.
Sync.Land continues past the grant.
This is now entering into a new phase,
past the concept,
and will be able
to be tested commercially.
The honest state of this after
a conceptual build is it needs more buyer
demand. And what streaming
has taught us is that we need
to be embracing the micro-sync
per-use license.
And we could use the x402
AI agents with Masumi.
We can have the licenses settled in Hydra
to be able to handle higher throughput
and cheaper fees. Sync.Land is taking
30 percent of each license on sale
and 70 percent goes to the artists.
For this phase, we're going
to be raising a pre-seed round.
We would love to come back to Project
Catalyst for any open source pieces.
I want to say thank you to the Cardano
community first and foremost
for believing in the Sync.Land vision and
for Project Catalyst and the reviewers.
And with that, goodbye.